hey guys this looks like a fun one it's
got a rectangle with three Circles of
diameter 3 4 and six smooshed in here
and we're supposed to find the distance
from here to here if you want to try it
on your own pause it right now CU I'm
going to solve it in 3 2 1 first let us
label the center of each of the circles
let's take this diameter and extend it
up here and let's split this into a
purple distance and a green distance
let's call the purple distance X and the
green distance y so ultimately we're
trying to find x + y I want to work on y
first let's look at these two larger
circles this one has a diameter of four
which means the radius is two and this
one has a diameter of six which means
the radius is three let's bring down the
green distance and find this
perpendicular segment since this is two
right here this distance would also be
two and this whole radius of three would
be broken up into one and two next let's
connect the centers of the circles and
that'll give us the hypotenuse of our
right triangle this piece is equal to
the radius of two and this piece is
equal to the radius of three and the
entire hypotenuse would have a length of
2 + 3 or 5 now let's mess around with
our new right triangle I'm thinking
Pythagorean theorem 1^ 2 + y^2 is = 5^2
and this will clean up it gives us 1 +
y^2 is = to 25 we can subtract one from
both sides and we get y^2 is equal to 24
now to get the Y by itself we can square
root both sides of the equation since Y
is a positive distance the square otk of
y^2 is just going to be Y and then we
can simplify the square root of 24 24 is
= to 4 * 6 and the < TK of 4 * 6 is
equal to the < TK 4 * the < TK 6 and
then the < TK of 4 is equal to 2 so Y is
equal to 2 * the < TK of 6 so we can
update this green distance to be 2un 6
and we can move it back up here now
let's work on the X this circle has a
diameter of three which means the radius
is 1.5 let's connect these two centers
which will be made up of this radius of
1.5 and this radius of two so the whole
thing will have a length of 3.5 then
let's drop this perpendicular and let's
find its distance since this largest
Circle had a diameter of six that means
the height of this rectangle is also
equal to six and then we can bring this
radius of two over here so we need 2
plus the purple distance plus 1.5 to
equal 6 that means our purple distance
is going to be equal to 2.5 and now
let's play with this triangle
Pythagorean theorem tells us 2.52 + x^2
is = to 3.52 2.52 is = 6.25 + x^2 and
then 3.52 is = 12.25 we can subtract
6.25 from both sides and we get x^2 is
equal to 6 and after we square root both
sides we get X is equal 2 the < TK of 6
that means that our purple distance will
be equal to the < TK of 6 and we can
bring that back up here so now we have
the question mark is going to be equal
to the purple < TK 6 plus the green 2un
6 and < TK 6 + 2un 6 is equal to 3un 6
and that is the answer to our question
let's put a box around it how exciting I
just got a haircut what do you guys
think